Hello, this is the video about the second task.
And here again we have been given a picture which
is on the right-hand side of the screen again.
And this picture is what we would like to draw.
We would like to draw a picture
which looks like this one.
So therefore we have given in our
task: We should at least draw a trunk
and two branches and some leaves.
This actually helps us also understand
how we can structure our code.
Because now we have given parts which we
can identify and which we want to draw.
Like if you want to define
our scene we can simply say:
We have a trunk, and we have
branches, and we have leaves.
Now, of course we haven't defined them yet but we
know that we can just define blanks for each part.
And so we have a blank for trunk,
for branches, and for leaves.
And now we can fill in those parts.
Now let's specify the types of our
values for trunk, branches, and leaves.
We want to construct a picture, and the
trunk shall therefore also be a picture
as well as the other ones; so branches
are also a picture, and so are leaves.
Okay. Now let's start with the trunk.
The trunk is the brown part
which you can see here.
So we want to draw a rectangle—a solid
one again—as we did in the previous task.
And we can look into the API in
order to search for functions.
We can open it right here or I have opened it in
a new tab—so we can search here for all parts.
So if we search for rectangle, then we find the
rectangle, solidRectangle, and thickRectangle.
And as I mentioned before, we want
to draw a solid rectangle here.
So we can use this function
by giving width and height.
The solid rectangle that we draw in
this case shall be higher than wide.
So let's just say we have one and
four as the values for the trunk.
Let's have a look at how this looks.
Oh, it's rather thick.
But we can have a helper here in
order to figure out measurements.
Which is the coordinate plane.
This is simply a picture which we can
add to our other pictures by combining
coordinatePlane and solidRectangle.
We get something which looks like this.
Now we see how wide these elements are.
And if we compare it to our other picture here, we
might guess that we can actually reduce the width
of the trunk if we want to have a picture which
looks exactly like the one that we've been given.
Actually, the task just says
similar—but let's try to
make it very close to the
one that we've been given.
So, I guess it's about half
of the version here. So: run.
So that's fine. Okay now we've got a trunk
already, but it's not colored correctly.
Yeah, we can change the color by using the
colored function, which we used before.
And we can find it in the API here
and again, there are colors defined.
And, yeah, let's look for brown.
Yeah, there's brown defined as well,
so we can use this color as well.
So we can say: colored brown
solid rectangle—all right.
I just removed the coordinate
plane for now—for a moment.
Let's have a look at this picture
now. Now we have our trunk!
And let's continue with the branches.
The branches are these parts here.
So how do we get this part?
We can draw rectangles, but they
are either horizontal or vertical.
So let's just assume we have a rectangle there
again for the branches and they are maybe
wider than—
or let's say—yeah—
let's make this one
about half of the width of the trunk.
And then just a length.
I guess two at this time.
And now we have one part of the branch which
we can't see because there is a trunk already.
So let's just draw the branch for the moment.
I remove the trunk.
Yeah, there we have now something like this.
But we want this to be rotated;
this would be nice, I guess.
So let's look up if we can rotate something.
And there we have a function, rotated!
And we can rotate a picture by
giving the angle and the picture.
The angle shall be given in radians,
so we shall keep this in mind.
So now we have this
part here—rotate it—in radians—so we have to
think about how much we want to rotate it.
We want to rotate it by 45 degrees and two pi is
a whole circle, so this would be a quarter of pi.
And now, in brackets here.
And now we try this one, how it looks like.
Now we rotated counterclockwise by 45
degrees and we have one part of the branch.
And we have to color it again,
so let's say this is brown again.
And we have to somehow duplicate what
we've already got for the other branch.
But this time we do not want to rotate
it clockwise, but counterclockwise.
So the other part shall also be
colored brown, so that's why we can
just insert it inside the bracket.
And there we want to have it rotated in the
other direction so that's minus pi over four
And it's the same rectangle we want to add here.
So, well, this is not
exactly what we want to have.
Because now we have the branches crossed
but obviously that's not what we want.
We want the branches to go from the trunk, so let's
add the trunk again here in order to view this.
And now we have to move parts in the
—oh, I removed the b here—branches,
within our picture in order to
move those parts here correctly.
And therefore we can use
the coordinate plane again.
So I add the coordinate plane.
And now let's have a look
at what's happening here.
So we have to move our branch parts; we have to
move both branch parts; we have to move the one
that's going to the right to the upper right
and the one that's going to the upper left.
We have to move both!
And this one has to be moved
to the right and to the top.
And we can see the values that we have to
move it by looking in the coordinate plane.
So when we move it to the
right, let's just do this first.
So we have translated and we want to move
the branch that's going to the upper left.
We want to move this one to the left direction.
and it's rather hard to see
- so maybe zoom in a bit.
And I guess this is about
three quarters of the whole square
here so this one should be minus 0.75.
And we don't move it to the top yet.
So just like this and we move the
Let's have a look!
If that's what we want?
Now that looks quite good!
So we want to move the other part as
well - so this one is the other part.
So here again we say translated!
And we move this one in the other direction.
So it's plus 0.75, so!
And we can write it like this and then we've
got the function for the other direction.
So now we have a redundant bracket here.
We don't need this one because
it's just a single value.
We can remove this bracket.
We require the bracket here,
because of this minus here.
We have to have a bracket around it,
so that the minus gets applied to just
the single value making it negative.
But if we have a positive value
we do not require the bracket.
Okay so this will still
result in a valid program.
And now let's have a look again at our picture
- because we have to move this one upwards.
How far do we have to move it?
Well if you look here - so
it's 210 and a half.
So that should be two and a half.
So we can say two and a half
and two and a half and move this trunk
part, these branches, up the trunk.
And now we have the branches and the trunk!
Now we need the leaves!
And here we require again
a circle - a solid circle.
And the function for this
is of course solidCircle
and we give the radius of the
circle that we want to have.
So now we can have a look again in the
coordinate plane and already applied
the size that we want to have.
So if we have a look here then we might want to
have the circle around this point here, right?
So that it's going like this roughly.
So this would be a radius of two.
Let's just apply this one and have a look.
Well it's not yet at the correct position.
So it's at (0,0) we want to have it at
(0,3), so we have to move the circle upwards.
So we can say translated and then - zero
- because we don't want to move it in the
horizontal direction but we want to move it
upwards that's why we add this three, so!
And now we shall have our branches
our leaves at the right position.
But the color is of course wrong at the
moment so we have to change the color.
And again we can use colored for this and this
time we choose green as the color of course.
Now we've got basically our tree.
We can remove the coordinate plane.
And now we are done with our picture.
But we may improve our code a bit
- if we want to - we want to!
So we can see some parts
here that we could improve.
We've structured our code already into
different parts, but we have a rather
deep part here with - well, we color
both the trunk and the branches brown.
So we could move this into
another value and we could say we want
to have the wooden parts together.
So we can say we have the wooden
parts and - wood is picture again.
And wood consists of trunk and branches.
And this is the wooden parts so -
well, there's not much gained yet.
But we can say both of them are colored brown
because in both parts we write colored brown.
So now we can just apply this to both parts.
We can remove the color down
here and can remove it here.
And then
we can - we have still the
same picture but have -
shorter definitions within branches and trunk -
and just these colored brown ones for both parts!
Just to keep in mind - because it's
helpful for reading programs as well.
So when you get a program, it's helpful when it's
structured so that others could read it better.
And it's also helpful for programming
when you want to change later stuff
if you have structured
your code and named values.
So you can identify parts - like for
instance the wooden parts and the leaves.
And the wooden parts consist of the
trunk and the branches and so on.
And yeah - try to avoid redundant brackets
and enter the types for your given parts.